whatismyip.com 2018-12-29

# Privacy Policy - WhatIsMyIP.com®

WHATISMYIP.COM®

WhatIsMyIP.com® (the “Website”) is a website owned by Innovation HQ, Inc., a corporation incorporated pursuant to the laws of Antigua, with a postal address of P.O. Box 990 Lower Factory Road, St. Johns, Antigua (the “Provider”, “We”, or “Us”).

We want you to understand how we use the information that you provide to us. This Privacy Policy sets out how we obtain and use the “Personal Information” which you provide us. Personal Information may include your name, address, telephone number, email address, date of birth, and other data which may directly or indirectly identify you.  
As the legal environment, technology, and operations change, it may become necessary for us to make changes to this Privacy Policy and all such changes will be posted on the Website.

How We Gather Information  
We gather Personal Information through the Website in several different ways:

a) Through our Website sign-up/registration process; 

c) Through providing support to our registered account holders; and

d) Through your payment to third-party payment processors such as Paypal. 

We also gather other information (“Other Information”), which cannot identify you unless it is used in conjunction with actual Personal Information. For example, we may collect your Public IPv6 address, your public IPv4 address, your local IP address, your location, and your Internet Service Provider’s identity, but without knowing your Personal Information, such Other Information cannot generally be used by us to identify you, and as such is not considered Personal Information.

The purpose of us collecting Personal Information and Other Information, is to enable you to use our services, which include inter alia, IP detection services, Internet speed test services, IP lookup services, IP change and hiding services, as well as other services available on or via our Website (the “Services”). Even when visiting the Website, Other Information may be automatically obtained, however this will not disclose your Personal Information unless you are logged in to your account with Us.

We may receive and store certain information whenever you visit the Website. We may use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer the Website, and to help identify you. Your IP address may also be used to gather broad demographic information, and for other purposes. Any information you voluntarily provide to us is used for such purposes as customizing your Website experience, allowing us to respond to your requests and comments, and improving the Website.

We reserve the right to perform statistical analyses of user behavior and characteristics in order to measure interest in and use of the various areas of the Website and to inform advertisers of such information as well as the number of users that have been exposed to or clicked on their advertising banners. We will provide only aggregated data from these analyses to third parties. 

Additionally, users should be aware that although we take standard precautions to safeguard your Personal Information, when you voluntarily disclose personally identifiable information (e.g., name, e-mail address, telephone number, etc. on our Website which does not encrypt or otherwise secure that information other than by standard web server technology, along with any substantive information disclosed in your communication, this Personal Information may be subject to unauthorized collection by third parties and that unauthorized activity is beyond our control.

We also may employ agents to fulfill functions on our behalf, such as providing marketing assistance, analyzing data, preparing and maintaining site content, processing credit card payments and providing customer service. These agents have access to user and customer information as required in order to help them perform their functions on our behalf, but they are not allowed to use that information for any other purpose.

Users Must be Age of Majority  
Persons under the age of majority in their jurisdiction must ask their parents or legal guardians for permission before sending any information about themselves to us, or via the Website or to PayPal or another third party payment processor.

Use of Personal Information  
We may use your email address to send you news about or updates about the Website, our services, or information related to our domain name inventory and the sale thereof, and to respond to customer service issues or comments and questions received from you. Upon request, We will allow any user to “opt out” of further promotional contacts at any time. If you do not wish to receive notification of special offers or news and/or updates to our site(s), please [contact us](https://www.whatismyip.com/contact-us/).

If you purchase a subscription or service from our Website, credit card or other financial information that is collected is used for billing and payment purposes, including by third a party payment processors such as PayPal, may be submitted to the appropriate financial institution in order to process your credit card or other financial transaction, and will not be provided to any other person or party. You may be subject to the privacy policy of a third party processor such as PayPal. When you make a purchase through PayPal, We generally are only provided by PayPal with your email address and name, together with the amount paid.

Our Use of Cookies and Web Beacons  
You should be aware that non-personal information and data may be automatically collected through the standard operation of our Website’s internet servers or through the use of “cookies”. “Cookies” are small text files that a web site may use to recognize repeat users, facilitate the user’s ongoing access to and use of the site and allow a site to track usage behavior and compile aggregate data that will allow content improvements and targeted advertising, amongst other uses. Cookies are not programs that come onto a user’s system and damage files. Generally, cookies work by assigning a unique number to the user that has no meaning outside the assigning site. Users should be aware that We may not be able to control the use of cookies or the resulting information by advertisers or third parties hosting data for us. If a user does not want information collected through the use of cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows the user to deny or accept the cookie feature; however, users should note that cookies may be necessary to provide the user with certain features (e.g., customized delivery of information) available on the Website.

Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on this site. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to Our users based on their visit to our Website and other sites on the Internet.  
Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network Privacy Policy.

We use third party advertisements on this Website. Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP, the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed. This is generally used for geo-targeting purposes or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited.  
You can choose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security. However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our Website as well as other websites. This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts.

Log Files  
As with most other websites, We collect and use the data contained in log files. The information in the log files may include your IP address, your ISP, the browser you used to visit Our Website, the time you visited our Website and which pages you visited throughout our Website. 

Transfer of Customer Information  
Customer information is a valuable business asset. If for any reason We transfer or divest ourselves of our business assets, our customer information may be transferred as one of these business assets.

Release of Information When Required  
We will release customer information to the appropriate authorities if we are required to do so by law. We may also release such information if we feel it is necessary in order to protect our rights or the rights of our customers, affiliates, partners, or any other party, and for purposes of protection from fraud and credit risk.

External Links

The Website may contain links or references to other websites to which this Privacy Policy does not apply. These sites are not owned or controlled by us and We are not responsible for the collection, use and disclosure of personal information or the privacy practices of other organizations or other websites to which our site may refer visitors or provide links for. When submitting Personal Information on such other websites, we encourage you to read the privacy policy of those sites.

API

If you have registered for use of Our API and in the course of using same with or for third parties, you may be collecting and processing Personal Information, and as such you must comply with any applicable laws or regulations concerning your collection and use of such Personal Information. 

Consent

Consent to the collection, use and disclosure of Personal Information may be given in various ways. Consent can be express (e.g., orally, electronically or on a form you may submit, or implied (e.g., when you provide information necessary for a service you have requested, or in some circumstances where notice has been provided to you about our intentions with respect to your Personal Information and you have not withdrawn your consent for an identified purpose, such as by using an “opt out” option provided). Consent may be given by your authorized representative (such as a legal guardian or a person having a power of attorney). Generally, by providing us with Personal Information, we will assume that you consent to our collection, use and disclosure of such information for the purposes identified or described in this Privacy Policy, if applicable, or as otherwise described at the time of collection. You may withdraw your consent to our collection, use and disclosure of Personal Information at any time, subject to contractual and legal restrictions and reasonable notice, however, please note that if you withdraw your consent to certain uses of your personal information, we may no longer be able to provide certain of our services.

We do not collect, use or disclose your Personal Information other than as described in this Privacy Policy without your consent, unless permitted or required by law. We may be required or permitted under statute or regulation to collect, use or disclose personal information without your consent, for example in response to a court order or subpoena, to comply with local or federal regulations, or to collect a debt owed to us.

Your Data Protection Rights under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)  
If you are an individual resident of the European Economic Area (EEA), you may have the following data protection rights:  
• If you wish to access, correct, update, or request deletion of your personal information, you can do so at any time by [contacting us](https://www.whatismyip.com/contact-us/).  
• In addition, you can object to the processing of your personal information, ask us to restrict the processing of your personal information, or request portability of your personal information. Again, you can exercise these rights by [contacting us](https://www.whatismyip.com/contact-us/).  
• You have the right to opt-out of marketing communications we send you at any time. You can exercise this right by clicking on the "unsubscribe" or "opt-out" link in marketing emails we send you. To opt-out of other forms of marketing, please [contact us](https://www.whatismyip.com/contact-us/).  
• Similarly, if we have collected and processed your personal information with your consent, then you can withdraw your consent at any time. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect the processing of your personal information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent.  
• You have the right to complain to a data protection authority about our collection and use of your personal information. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority.  
We respond to all requests we receive from individuals wishing to exercise their data protection rights in accordance with applicable data protection laws. You may be required to identify yourself as a person to which the GDPR is applicable in order for us to extend GDPR-mandated privacy requirements to you, and we reserve our right to deny provision of our services to you if we in our sole discretion determine that we want to provide the services only to persons resident outside the European Economic Area (“EAA”). If you are a resident of the EEA and believe we maintain your personal data subject to the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), you may find out more information, including about the complaint procedure, here; <https://edps.europa.eu/data-protection/our-role-supervisor/complaints_en>. 

How to Contact Us

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with the Website, you can [let us know here](https://www.whatismyip.com/contact-us/), or write via snail mail at our above-noted mailing address. Any dispute arising between you and us with respect to privacy is subject to any applicable terms and conditions of use of the Website, and this Privacy Policy, including limitations on damages, arbitration, and jurisdiction.

The foregoing policies are effective as of May 15, 2018. This statement and the policies outlined herein are not intended to and do not create any contractual or other legal rights in or on behalf of any party.
